《普罗米修斯》
去找查理!
Get Charlie.
霍罗威博士!
Dr. Holloway!
查理!
Charlie!
干嘛?
What?
快来!
Come quick!
(苏格兰天空岛 2089年)
- 年代测定过了么? - 有35000年了 也许更久
- Did you date it? - Thirty-five thousand years. Maybe older.
你在开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
一样的星布局形状
It's the same configuration.
这个年代比其他的要早了千年
I mean, it's gotta predate the others by millennia.
他们是想要我们来这里并发现他们
I think they want us to come and find them.
是啊
Yeah.
(科学考察船: 普罗米修斯号)
(船员人数: 17名)
(日期: 2093年12月21日)
(距离地球: 327兆公里)
(目的地: 不明)
(伊丽莎白·肖博士  神经-面罩  连接建立)
那人怎么了?
What happened to that man?
他死了
He died.
你为什么不帮他们?
Why aren't you helping them?
他们不需要我的帮助
They don't want my help.
他们的神和我们可不一样
Their God is different than ours.
他为什么会死?
Why did he die?
因为无论早晚 每个人都会死
Because sooner or later, everyone does.
像妈妈一样么?
Like Mummy?
像妈妈一样
Like Mummy.
她去了哪里?
Where do they go?
每个人都去自己的归宿
Everyone has their own word.
天堂
Heaven.
乐园
Paradise.
不管它叫什么 反正是美好的地方
Whatever it's called, it's someplace beautiful.
你怎么知道是美好的?
How do you know it's beautiful?
那是我的信仰
That's what I choose to believe.
你选择相信什么呢 艾丽?
What do you believe, Ellie?
(伊丽莎白·肖博士  神经-面罩  连接终止)
早上好 大卫
Good morning, David.
发送讯息
Transmitting message.
没有回应
No response.
然而这种发音...
Whilst this articulation...
被证实是印欧语系后裔的语言...
is attested in the Indo-European descendants...
作为一种纯粹的附属语言构成...
as a purely paralinguistic form...
其语音形成形式可以追溯至...
it is phonemic in the ancestral form dating back...
5000年以前
five millennia or more.
现在开始练习施莱谢尔寓言
Let's attempt Schleicher's fable.
跟我念
Repeat after me.
很好
Perfect.
- 劳伦斯先生 - 什么?
- Mr. Lawrence? - Yes?
- 复写纸 先生 - 谢谢
- Flimsy, sir. - Thank you.
你又做到了一次 那可是血肉啊!
You do that once too often. It's only flesh and blood!
迈克尔·乔治·哈特利 你是哲学家
Michael George Hartley, you're a philosopher.
而你太笨了
And you're barmy.
- 真的很疼! - 当然痛啦
- It damn well hurts! - Certainly, it hurts.
那你有什么窍门?
Well, what's the trick, then?
窍门 威廉·帕特
The trick, William Potter
就是别光想着痛
is not minding that it hurts.
窍门 威廉·帕特...
The trick, William Potter...
就是别光想着痛
is not minding that it hurts.
窍门 威廉·帕特...
The trick, William Potter...
就是别想着痛
is not minding that it hurts.
注意:
Attention:
抵达目的地
Destination threshold.
注意:
Attention:
抵达目的地
Destination threshold.
注意: 抵达目的地
Attention: Destination threshold.
拿袍子
Robe.
多久?
How long?
2年 4个月 18天36小时 15分
Two years, four months, 18 days 36 hours, 15 minutes.
有人员伤亡没?
Any casualties?
伤亡情况 女士?
Casualties, ma'am?
有没有人死了?
Has anyone died?
不 女士 每个人都很好
No, ma'am. Everyone is fine.
那好 叫他们起来
Well, then wake them up.
放松一下 肖博士
Try to relax, Dr. Shaw.
我叫大卫
My name is David.
你的身体处于休克痉挛状态
Your mind and body are in a state of shock...
这是长期休眠造成的
as a result of the stasis.
没事的 相当正常
It's all right. Perfectly normal.
艾丽
Ellie.
我们到了 宝贝
We're here, baby.
给你 给你
There, there.
喝多点水 吃多点流体食物
Drink plenty of water. Drink plenty of fluids.
有助于恢复肌肉组织
Hydration aids muscle mass.
各位船员 应进食高热量的奶酪
All crew, consume shakes with high caloric content.
那是什么玩意儿?
What the hell is that?
是圣诞节
It's Christmas.
我们需要过节日来显示时间仍在运转
We need the holidays to show time is still moving.
任务简报开始了 舰长
Mission briefing is about to start, captain.
你何不快点前去呢
Might wanna make your way down.
我可没被通知到
Well, I haven't had any breakfast yet.
没占座吧?
Is this seat taken?
我叫密尔本 生物学家 很高兴见到你
Hi, I'm Millburn, Biology. Nice to meet you.
好的
Okay.
瞧 别介意 但是...
Look, no offense, but...
我已经睡了2年了
I've been asleep two years.
我像是来交朋友的么
I ain't here to be your friend.
我只是来赚钱的
I'm here to make money.
懂了没?
You got that?
好吧
Okay.
我赌100点数这次是做地貌环境改造调查
I bet a hundred credits it's a terraforming survey.
不 如果是一次调查 他们会跟我们说的
No, if it's a survey, they would tell us.
这是一次公司行为 他们不会跟我们说废话的
It's a corporate run, they're not telling us shit.
来吧
Come on.
- 那就100点吧 - 好的 你来吧
- A hundred. - All right, you're on.
你看上去很紧张 艾丽
You look nervous, El.
- 我要尽力让自己的脚站住  - 我知道你会这样
- I'll try to keep my feet on the ground. - I know you will.
早上好
Good morning.
这话是对那些我亲自雇的人说的
For those of you I hired personally...
真的很高兴再见到你们
it's nice to see you again.
剩下的人注意了 我叫梅瑞迪斯·维克丝
For the rest of you, I am Meredith Vickers.
我的工作就是监督你们好好工作的
It's my job to make sure you do yours.
好吧...开始播放吧
Okay, then. On with the show.
维兰德企业
Weyland Corporation.
建造更好的世界
Building better worlds.
大家好 朋友们
Hello, friends.
我叫皮特·维兰德
My name is Peter Weyland.
我是你们的雇主
I am your employer.
这段录制于2091年6月22日
I am recording this, 22 June, 2091.
如果你们在收看的话...
And if you're watching it...
说明你们已经抵达目的地
you have reached your destination.
我或已早死
And I am long dead.
愿我安息吧
May I rest in peace.
今天你们中间有个人 他的名字叫大卫
There's a man sitting with you today. His name is David.
他就像我应有的儿子一样
And he is the closest thing to a son I will ever have.
很可惜 他不是人类
Unfortunately, he is not human.
他不会老...
He will never grow old...
也不会死
and he will never die.
而且他也不会懂得孤芳自赏...
And yet he is unable to appreciate these remarkable gifts...
因为需要一样东西是大卫不会具有的
for that would require the one thing that David will never have.
就是灵魂
A soul.
我花费终生去找寻这些答案:
I have spent my entire lifetime contemplating the questions:
我们来自哪里?
Where do we come from?
我们的使命是什么?
What is our purpose?
我们死后会怎样?
What happens when we die?
最终有两个人他们让我相信
And I have found two people who convinced me
相信答案已唾手可得了
they're on the verge of answering them.
霍罗威和肖博士 请起身
Drs. Holloway and Shaw, if you would please stand.
据我所知 他俩负责此次任务
As far as you're concerned, they're in charge.
泰坦族人普罗米修斯想要给予人类与诸神同等的地位...
The Titan Prometheus wanted to give mankind equal footing with the gods...
为此 他被逐出奥林匹斯山
and for that, he was cast from Olympus.
我的朋友 神回归的时刻终于到来了
Well, my friends, the time has finally come for his return.
博士们 请吧
Doctors, please.
你们开始吧
The floor is yours.
好的 哇哦
Okay, wow.
好吧
All right.
我可从没见过幽灵讲话的
I never had to follow a ghost before.
好吧 让我们看看我们为什么来这的原因
Okay, let me show you why you guys are here.
这些是世界各地考古采集的图片
These are images of archeological digs from all over the Earth.
那是...
That's...
埃及人 玛雅人 苏美尔人 巴比伦人
Egyptian, Mayan, Sumerian, Babylonian.
最后那个是夏威夷人 然后美索不达米亚人
That's Hawaiian there at the end, then Mesopotamian.
这个是我们最近的发现
Now, this one here is our most recent discovery.
在苏格兰的天空岛发现的一张35000年前的洞穴壁画
It's a 35,000-year-old cave painting from the Isle of Skye in Scotland.
这些古代文明
These are ancient civilizations.
她们相隔数个世纪
They were separated by centuries.
她们之间没有任何联系 但是...
They shared no contact with one another, and yet....
这些相同的图像...
The same pictogram...
显示人类崇拜一种巨人生物 指向着的这些星星...
showing men worshipping giant beings, pointing to the stars...
每张图像都显示着同样的内容
was discovered at every last one of them.
唯一匹配这星图的星系...
And the only galactic system that matched...
距离地球非常远...
was so far from Earth that there's no way...
以至于这些远古地球文明...
that these primitive, ancient civilizations...
不可能知晓它的存在
could have possibly known about it.
但事实确实发生了...
But it just so happens...
那个星图体系中...
that that system...
有颗太阳...
has a sun...
很像我们的太阳系
a lot like ours.
根据我们的长波扫描 好像那里有颗行星
And, based on our long-range scans, there seemed to be a planet.
这颗行星的一个卫星上...
Just one planet with a moon...
可维系生命
capable of sustaining life.
而今早我们到了这里
And we arrived there this morning.
那你是说我们来这儿
So you're saying we're here
就因为你们两个小孩在洞里找到的一张图 对不对?
because of a map you two kids found in a cave. Is that right?
- 不 - 是
- No. - Yeah.
不 不是图 而是个邀请
No. Not a map, an invitation.
来自谁?
From who?
我们叫他们工程师
We call them Engineers.
工程师?
Engineers?
你介意说下他们创造什么东西的么?
Do you mind telling us what they engineered?
他们创造了我们
They engineered us.
胡说
Bullshit.
你有什么证据能支持你的理论么?
Okay, so do you have anything to back that up?
如果你低估了数世纪之久的达尔文进化论 那就...
Look, if you're willing to discount centuries of Darwinism, that's....
你怎么知道的?
But how do you know?
我不知道
I don't.
但我选择去相信
But it's what I choose to believe.
博士们
Doctors.
维克丝小姐想在我们这次冒险之前同你们说几句
Miss Vickers would like to have a quick word before the adventure begins.
哇哦 好地方
Wow, nice place.
事实上这是飞船的独立舱
It's actually a separate module
具有自给的生命维系系统
with its own self-contained life support.
空气 食物
Air, food.
任何能让维克丝小姐在恶劣环境下生存的东西都有
Anything Miss Vickers would need to survive a hostile environment.
她就像活在救生舱里一样
Okay, so she lives on a lifeboat.
是啊
Yes.
我知道
I do.
我可不会冒险
I like to minimize risk.
大卫 给博士们来一杯怎么样?
David, why don't you make the doctors a drink?
我要杯伏特加 摇下
I'll take a vodka. Up.
查理 看这个
Charlie, look.
是个鲍林医疗舱
It's a Pauling Med-Pod.
他们仅制造了十几个这样的
They only made a dozen of these.
肖女士
Miss Shaw.
请描述你的病情
Please verbally state the nature of your injury.
请不要触摸那个
Please don't touch that.
这是非常昂贵的仪器
It's a very expensive piece of machinery.
这是外科手术用的 你要这个干什么?
It does bypass surgery. What do you need it for?
别搞混了我们之间的关系
There might be some confusion about our relationship.
维兰德先生有足够理由赞助你们这次任务
Weyland found you impressive enough to fund this mission.
但我很确定你们所说的工程师...
But I'm fairly certain your Engineers are scribblings...
无非是生活在肮脏洞穴里的一帮野人而已
of savages living in dirty little caves.
如果我错了 如果你们找到了你们所说的生命...
But let's say I'm wrong, and you do find these beings down there...
不许和他们接触...
you won't engage them...
不许和他们说话
you won't talk to them.
什么都不许做而是直接回来向我汇报
You will do nothing but report back to me.
维克丝小姐 是不是还有什么安排...
Miss Vickers, is there an agenda that...
你没有告诉我们的?
you're not telling us about?
我的公司...
My company...
花了一万亿美元找到了这个地方并把你们带来
paid a trillion dollars to find this place and bring you.
如果你能自己凑这笔钱的话 霍罗威博士...
Had you raised the monies yourself, Mr. Holloway...
那我们将乐意遵照你的安排
we'd happily be pursuing your agenda.
但你没钱
But you didn't.
所以你是雇员
And that makes you an employee.
我们不能和他们交流...
But if we can't make contact...
那你需要我们来这干吗?
why did you even bring us here?
维兰德先生是个迷信的人
Weyland was a superstitious man.
他要坚定的信仰者留在船上
He wanted a true believer onboard.
干杯!
Cheers.
没有回应?
So no response?
不好意思 没有
I'm sorry, no.
也许他们不懂你的（交流方式）
Maybe they didn't understand it.
你的课程进展如何 大卫?
How are your lessons going, David?
我花了两年解析了几十种古代语言的根源
I spent two years deconstructing dozens of ancient languages to their roots.
我自信我能和他们交流...
I'm confident I can communicate with them...
假如你的论文正确的话
provided your thesis is correct.
"假如是正确的" 很好
"Provided it's correct." That's good.
所以纸上谈兵被称为论文嘛 博士
That's why they call it a thesis, doctor.
你笑什么?
What are you smiling about?
拉威尔先生 钱斯先生 带她下去吧
Mr. Ravel, Mr. Chance, take her down.
- 收到  - 是 舰长
- Roger that. - Yes, captain.
下降轨道已经绘制
Descent trajectory mapped.
情况如何?
How we doing?
好极了
Great.
可以了 头儿
All right, boss.
所有人员注意...
All personnel...
我是舰长
this is the captain.
准备进入
Brace for entry.
遵命 舰长
Yes, captain.
你也一样坐好了 维克丝
That means you too, Vickers.
所有系统启动
All systems online.
大气成分如何?
What is the atmosphere?
大气含有...
Atmosphere is...
71％氮气...
71 percent nitrogen...
21％氧气...
21 percent oxygen...
微量的氩气
traces of argon gas.
哇哦 这天气
Whoa, now, that's weather.
就像家一样
Just like home.
如果你通过呼吸系统呼吸的话
If you're breathing through an exhaust pipe.
二氧化碳超过3％
CO2 is over 3 percent.
曝露在外2分钟 你就会死
Two minutes without a suit, you're dead.
海拔真高
Peak portside.
哇哦 52000英尺!
Whoa, 52,000!
这让珠穆朗玛峰看起来像个小弟弟了
It makes Everest look like a baby brother.
好带 我们下去逛逛吧
All right, take us around.
我们将利用它当作进入点
We'll use that as our point of entry.
地形图出来了 有好几个硬点
Terrain data rezzing up. We've got a couple of hard spots.
可能是金属
Could be metal.
没有信号 没有热源
No radio, no heat source.
没有人在家
Nobody's home.
沙漠里什么都没有...
There is nothing in the desert...
却没有人不贪求
and no man needs nothing.
你说什么?
What was that?
只是我喜欢的一部电影台词
Just something from a film I like.
穿过那个通道
Let's go through that gateway.
船速保持100节
Reduce airspeed by a hundred knots.
正在穿过 慢点稳点
Going through. Nice and slow.
稳住 伙计们
Keep it steady, boys.
那里
There.
不 你干什么?
No, what are you doing?
霍罗威博士 你为何不坐下啊?
Dr. Holloway, why don't you take a seat?
就在那里 上帝不会创造直线
Right there. God does not build in straight lines.
右舷 山谷里!
Starboard side, this valley!
舰长 你能降落在那里吗?
Captain could you put us down there?
如果我做不到就没啥好处了
I wouldn't be any good if I couldn't do that.
拉威尔先生 90右转舵度
Mr. Ravel, starboard 90 degrees.
- 一英里 左舷  - 一英里 左舷
- One mile, port bow. - One mile, port bow.
启动登陆步序
Engage landing sequence.
转手动修正
Switch to manual.
- 开始登陆  - 放松
- Commence landing. - Easy.
- 收到  - 是的 宝贝 是的
- Roger that. - Yeah, baby, yeah.
登陆前5秒
Bringing her down in five.
- 准备RCS推进器  - 四
- Preparing RCS thrusters. - Four.
二  慢点
Two. Easy does it.
引擎系统停止
Generator systems are inactive.
当前温度是2.724K
Temperature is at 2.724 K.
舰长 请你让搜索队伍穿戴齐整...
Captain, would you tell the survey team to suit up...
在气舱和我们会合
and meet us in the airlock.
还有6小时就天黑了
Only six hours left of daylight.
- 留待明晨再去吧  - 不 不 不
- Leave it till morning. - No, no, no.
今天是圣诞节 舰长...
It's Christmas, captain...
我想打开我的礼物
and I want to open my presents.
嘿 小子
You, boy.
你跟着我们
You're coming with us.
真是我的荣幸啊
I'd be delighted.
注意: 入口将在5分钟内打开
Attention: Ramp will open in five minutes.
杰克逊...
Hey, Jackson...
你要这个干什么?
what's that for?
为了安全考察
Expedition security.
我的任务就是让每个人安全的回来
My job is to make sure everybody is nice and safe.
这只是科学考察 不需要武器
This is a scientific expedition. No weapons.
那好吧
All right, then.
祝你们好运了
Good luck with that.
大卫 你为什么穿这套装束?
David, why are you wearing a suit, man?
你说什么?
I beg your pardon?
你是用不着呼吸的 记得么?
You don't breathe, remember?
那为什么要穿戴成这样?
So why wear a suit?
我被设计成这样的
I was designed like this...
因为你们人类和同类模样的人交流会比较惬意
because you people are more comfortable interacting with your own kind.
不穿戴的话 就没有意义了
If I didn't wear the suit, it would defeat the purpose.
和你猜想的差不多是么?
They're making you guys pretty close, huh?
不太一样 我希望是
Not too close, I hope.
注意: 入口将会在15秒内打开
Attention: Ramp will open in 15 seconds.
入口即将打开 五 四 三 二 一
Ramp will open in five, four, three, two, one.
这只是人类的一小步
This is just one small step for mankind.
说真的?
Seriously?
你们准备好开始了吗?我就知道你们的
You ready to do this? I know you are.
费菲尔德
Hey, Fifield.
我要你看下这个建筑物
I want a spectrograph on this.
我想知道这个是自然形成的还是人造的
I want to know if it's natural or if somebody put it there.
我可说不准它是不是自然形成
I can't tell you if it's natural or not.
但我能告诉你的是 它是中空的
But what I can tell you is, it's hollow.
普罗米修斯号 你们看到了么?
Prometheus, are you seeing this?
收到
Affirmative.
看到了
We see it.
准备好了么?
Okay, ready?
- 好了  - 开始吧
- Yeah. - Let's do it.
- 你先  - 你先
- After you. - After you.
好的
Okay.
小心
Careful.
普罗米修斯号 我们进去了
Prometheus, we're going in.
收到
Copy that.
这后面是什么?
What's back here?
像是条走廊吗?
Some kind of a corridor?
费菲尔德 把这个建筑网格化
Mr. Fifield, let's get a grid of the structure.
我需要整个内部结构
I want the whole interior.
如果这里有什么东西值得看的话...
If there's anything in here worth looking at...
这些小狗能找的到
these pups'll find them.
"小狗"
"Pups"?
嗯 小狗 我的小狗
Yeah, pups. My pups.
普罗米修斯号 开始绘制数据
Prometheus, we are now mapping.
收到
Copy that.
我真没想到
Well, I'll be damned.
费菲尔德 有读数么?
Fifield, you got a read?
有的
Yeah.
是的这边走
Pups are saying this way.
看看这
Look at this.
噢 查理
Oh, Charlie.
天啊
Jesus.
阳光在加热水
The sunlight is heating the water.
检查下你的仪表
Check out the humidity.
是的 看看二氧化碳含量
Yeah, and look at the CO2 levels.
外面全是呈毒性的 这里完全没有
Outside it's completely toxic, and in here there's nothing.
这里是可呼吸的
It's breathable.
你到底在干什么?
What are you doing?
- 别像个傻子一样  - 别疑神疑鬼的
- Don't be an idiot. - Don't be a skeptic.
一定有什么在产生这里的大气
There's something generating an atmosphere.
大卫?
David?
- 霍罗威博士是对的 - 比地球还干净...
- Dr. Holloway is correct. - Cleaner than Earth...
明显
actually.
他们进行过环境改造
They were terraforming.
拜托不要这样
Please don't do...
我再也不要戴着这些东西了
I'm not wearing this thing anymore.
祝我好运 宝贝
Wish me luck, baby.
听到吗?不要摘下你的头盔
Do you copy? Do not remove your headgear.
你这疯子
You crazy bastard.
连接我们衣服上的摄像头...
Connect our suit cameras...
如果你想继续观看这场畸形秀
if you want to continue watching this freak show.
我们要拿掉头盔了
We are taking our helmets off.
收到 改变接受讯号数据方式
Copy that. Switching feeds.
来吧 把赌注兑现吧
Well, come on. Pay up.
- 兑现什么? - "兑现"是什么意思?
- Pay what? - What do you mean, "Pay what"?
那里有东西在制造可呼吸的气体
Something is manufacturing breathable air down there.
那就意味着地貌环境改造
That, mate is terraforming.
不 不 赌的是我们来这儿干什么
No, no. The bet was why we came here.
如果你是说那个死老头想和火星人谈谈的话 那我付
If you said a dead old man wanted to talk to Martians, I'd pay.
拜托 100点数
Come on, a hundred credits.
用这个去让维克丝小姐跳个大腿舞 你认为怎样?
Put it towards a lap dance with Miss Vickers. How about that?
这儿达到零下12度了
It's minus 12 in here.
那么为何这里的水没有结冰呢?
So why is this water not frozen?
可能不是水
Maybe it ain't water.
可能是火星人的尿
Maybe it's Martian piss.
那就是你的科学理论性?
That's your scientific theory?
是不是?生物学家?
Is it? Mr. Biology?
不管它是什么 它肯定是胶质的
Whatever it is, it sure is collagenous.
某种沉淀物 也许吧
Some kind of sediment, perhaps.
了不起
Impressive.
那是什么
What was that?
大卫?
David?
大卫!
那是什么
What is that?
大卫!
David?
艾丽!
Ellie!
那到底是什么
What was that?
我真高兴我们没带任何武器
I'm really glad we didn't bring weapons.
- 来吧 艾丽 我们走 - 这是谁的馊主意?
- Come on, El. Let's go. - Whose idea was that?
跟上!
Keep up!
快点!
Come on!
他去了哪里?
Where did he go?
等下 等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
在那里 在那里 在那里
There it is. There it is. There it is.
天啊 查理 我们找到了他们
Oh, my God, Charlie. We found them.
"他们"是什么意思?
What do you mean "them"?
就是他们 艾丽
It is them, Ellie.
看上去像扇门...
It looks like a door...
像是被什么砍掉了头
and he's been decapitated by it.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
他们是对的
They were right.
你想让他们怎样?错的?
What did you want them to be? Wrong?
大卫...
David...
告诉我你看的懂这些文字
please tell me you can read that.
也许
Perhaps.
不行 我要离开这里
No, I'm out of here.
费菲尔德 你去哪里
Hey, Fifield, where are you going?
你说什么?
What?
听着 我只是个地质学家
Look, I'm just a geologist.
我喜欢石头 我爱石头!
I like rocks. I love rocks!
现在很明显你俩根本不在乎什么石头
Now it's clear you two don't give a shit about rocks.
看起来你只在乎巨大的死尸罢了
But what you do seem to care about is gigantic dead bodies.
因为我真的帮不上什么忙...
As I don't really have anything to contribute...
关于这个巨型死尸专业...
in the gigantic dead body arena...
我要回船上去了 如果你不介意的话
I want to go back to the ship, if you don't mind.
有什么人要和我一起走的么?你留下?
Anyone wanna join me, hey? You staying?
不 回船上比较好
No, ship's good.
是的 回船这个决定非常的好
Yeah. Ship very good.
祝贺你跟你的造物主
Congratulations on meeting your maker.
谢谢
Thank you.
你俩别走散了
Pull yourself together, man.
我还以为你是疯的
And I thought you were the crazy one.
你带有碳测定读取器吗?
Do you have the carbon reader?
谢谢
Thank you.
它死了多久?
How long's it been dead?
2000年左右吧
Two thousand years give or take.
你干什么 大卫?
What are you doing, David?
我要打开这门
I'm attempting to open the door.
等等 我们还不知道另一边有什么
Wait. We don't know what's on the other side.
哎呀 抱歉
Oops. Sorry.
看啊 福特 这是头部
Look, Ford. It's the head.
保存状况非常良好
An amazing state of preservation.
- 我们带走吧  - 嗯
- We'll take it in. - Yeah.
了不起的人像
Remarkably human.
漂亮的油画
Beautiful painting.
是壁画
It's a mural.
停
Stop.
停 别碰它
Stop. Don't touch it.
抱歉
Sorry.
请不要碰任何东西
Please, don't touch anything.
渗出来了
Sweating.
有机生物
Organic.
不
Oh, no.
查理 壁画开始改变了
Charlie, the murals are changing.
我想自我们进来后改变了这里的大气状况
I think we've affected the atmosphere in the room.
查理 你收到没?
Charlie, do you copy?
哦 头部!
Oh, the head!
福特 快啊 帮我把头包起来!
Ford, quick, help me bag the head!
- 老大  - 什么情况?
- Boss. - What you got?
一场风暴即将席卷而来
We got an incoming storm front.
含大量硅化物...
Silica...
具有很多静电 看上去不妙
and lots of static. This is not good.
我看到了
I see it.
地面人员...
Ground crew...
我是杰尼克
this is Janek.
我要求你们马上回来
I need you to hustle back right now.
地面人员 你们收到吗?
Ground crew, do you copy me?
时速每秒200公里的含硅化物的暴风要到来...
I got 200-kilometer winds of airborne silica...
其产生的静电足以吹干你们衣服
and enough static to fry your suit.
收到 先生
Copy that, sir.
我们要多花点时间
We need more time.
我将在15分钟内关闭外门
I'll be closing the outer doors in 15 minutes.
我衷心希望你能赶到
I sincerely hope you can make it.
查理!大卫!
Charlie! David!
我们要走了
We must leave now.
只是另一个坟墓
This is just another tomb.
大卫!
David!
- 数三下  - 二 三 上
- On three. - Two, three, up.
快点走了!
Let's go!
慢慢慢 小心
Easy, easy, easy. Careful.
大卫 我们要走了!
David, we are leaving!
快点!
Come on!
该死 他们已经起飞了
Damn it, they've already taken off.
快点 走吧
Come on, let's go.
普罗米修斯号呼叫地面人员
Prometheus to ground crew.
你们时间快不够了
You're running out of time.
好吧 快点 走了
All right, come on. Let's go.
再快点!
Go faster!
查理 那个头!
Charlie! The head!
艾丽 不!
Ellie, no!
你干什么?
What are you doing?
- 舱门5秒后关闭  - 妈的
- Hatch closure in five seconds. - Shit.
该死 等等!
Damn it, hold on!
该死
Goddamn it.
门在关闭
Door closing.
艾丽 别动!
Ellie, don't move!
查理!
Charlie!
抓住我的手!
Grab my hand!
不!
No!
不 艾丽!
No, Ellie!
艾丽!
Ellie!
搞定
Got it.
你那算是什么 艾丽?
So, what was that, Ellie?
你想毁了这次任务么
You could've compromised the mission.
更别说你还差点没命了!
Not to mention almost killing yourself!
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
没事
Yes.
谢谢你 大卫
Thank you, David.
不客气
My pleasure.
博士们 很高兴你们回来了
Doctors, it's real good to have you back,
密尔本和费菲尔德哪儿去了?
but where's Millburn and Fifield?
他们还没回来么?
Aren't they back yet?
- 帮我联系他们  - 好的
- Get them up for me. - All right.
我们来过这里啊 费菲尔德
We've been here before, Fifield.
不清楚 看上去都一样
I don't know. It all looks the same to me.
这是舰长在讲话 听着
Boys, this is the captain. Listen up.
现在外面一堆静电 还有风速...
Between the static electricity and the wind speed...
现在来找你们不安全
well, there ain't no safe way to come get you.
什么?
What?
温度下降很快
The temperature is dropping rapidly,
你们戴上头盔保持温度...
so get your helmets on and stay warm...
直到这场风暴结束
until the storm passes.
舰长...
Captain...
你能给我帮那个科学家和他那个狂热女友带个话么?
can you get a message to the scientist and his zealot girlfriend?
你这儿有笔吗?
You got a pen nearby?
不 不 我想我们得到了
No. No, I think we got it.
对他们说... 让他们去死
Tell them I said... themselves.
知道?
Copy?
知道了 好了 伙计们 把你们的头放低些...
Copy that. All right, boys, keep your head down...
我们会在早上去接你们
and we'll come get you in the morning.
现在去哪儿?
Well, which way now?
好吧
All right.
去哪儿?
Well, which way, huh?
样本消毒了 没有污染迹象
Sample is sterile. No contagion present.
大卫
David.
这么说他们都死了么?
So are they all dead?
啥?是谁?
What? Who?
他们都死了还是没死?
Are they all dead or aren't they?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们才刚来
We just got here.
扫描
Scan.
你很在乎他们的生死?
Do you care if they're dead?
维兰德先生在乎
Weyland cared.
肖博士
Dr. Shaw.
看看这个
Have a look at this.
- 这不是头骨  - 不是
- That's not an exoskeleton. - No.
我想这是个头盔
I think it's a helmet.
- 让我们看看能否拿走  - 我们应该...
- Let's see if we can lift it up. - We should...
看看哪儿能打开
be able to prize this open.
这对我们来说太重了 大卫?
It's too heavy for us. David?
小心点
Careful.
我一向小心
Like so.
他头上是些什么东西?
What is that on its head?
像是些新型细胞
It looks like new cells.
- 处于...  - 在突变中
- In a state of.... - Change.
是的
Yes.
突变成什么?
Changing into what?
让我们做个颅内复原怎么样?
Can you run a stem line into the locus coeruleus?
我想能骗过神经系统让它以为本体还活着
I think we can trick the nervous system into thinking it's still alive.
- 30安培  - 好
- Thirty amps. - Okay.
别多了
No more.
我来先做个切口
Let me make an incision.
好了
Okay.
上升至40
Go up, 40.
好 加至40
Okay, 40 up.
看到没?
Did you see that?
- 是的 - 嗯 看到了?
- Yes. - Yep. See?
再加10
Go up another 10.
好 再加10
Okay, up 10.
- 可能有点多了 下降10  - 好的
- Maybe it's a little too much. Go down 10. - Okay.
- 降10  - 再降个20
- Down 10. - Down another 20.
好的 我在试
Okay, I'm trying.
我在试 它没有下降
I'm trying, it's not going down.
全部下降 福特停下
Full down. Ford stop it.
天啊
Oh, God.
大卫 把它封闭起来!快!
David, contain it! Now!
封闭起来?快关掉!
Contain it? Turn it off!
天啊 是气味!
Oh, God. The smell!
天啊 看看那个
Oh, God, look at that.
看看那个
Look at that.
越来越糟了
It's getting worse.
凡人 仅此而已
Mortal, after all.
福特 取个样本
Ford, take a sample.
让我们看下
Let's have a look.
不 先生 我会负责处理的
No, sir, I will take care of it.
是的 先生 我明白 我抱歉
Yes, sir, understood. I'm sorry.
很不幸 稍微早产了
Fortunately, slightly premature.
当然 先生
Of course, sir.
维克丝小姐
Miss Vickers.
他对你说些什么 大卫?
What did he say, David?
我想他不想让我告诉你
I don't think he'd want me to tell you.
他到底说了什么?
What did he say?
抱歉...
I'm sorry...
那是保密的...
that's confidential.
看在老天的份上...
So help me God...
我要找到让你逃掉的绳子并割了它
I will find the cord that makes you run and I will cut it.
他说了什么?
What did he say?
他说:
He said:
"来点硬的"
"Try harder."
要来杯茶么 女士?
Cup of tea, ma'am?
提取遗传基因
Genetic view.
好的
Okay.
看下他的DNA
Let's have a look at its DNA.
分离DNA螺旋体
Isolate the strand.
好的
Okay.
准备好基因比对样本?
Compare it to the gene sample?
好的
Yeah.
交叉对比
Overlay.
处理中
Processing.
DNA匹配
DNA match.
天啊
Oh, my God.
是我们
It's us.
和我们一样
It's everything.
什么杀了他们?
What killed them?
大物始于小
Big things have small beginnings.
我有打断你么?
Am I interrupting?
我以为你挺消沉的
I thought you might be running low.
给你自己来一杯 伙计
Pour yourself a glass, pal.
谢谢 但我担心...
Thank you, but I'm afraid...
那对我真是浪费了
it would be wasted on me.
哦 我差点忘了你不是一个真正的男人
Right, I almost forgot you're not a real boy.
抱歉你的工程师都死了
I'm very sorry that your Engineers are all gone.
你觉得我们是白来这一趟了?
You think we wasted our time coming here, don't you?
你的问题取决于我如何理解
Your question depends on me understanding
你来这里想达成什么目的
what you hoped to achieve by coming here.
当然是找到我们的造物者
What we hoped to achieve was to meet our makers.
找寻答案
To get answers.
最初为什么他们创造我们
Why they even made us in the first place.
你认为为什么人类造了我呢?
Why do you think your people made me?
因为我们有能力
Because we could.
你能想象出这样多么令人失望...
Can you imagine how disappointing it would be...
当听到你的造物者说出刚刚你同样的话呢?
to hear the same thing from your creator?
好在你根本不懂得什么叫失望
I guess it's good you can't be disappointed.
是的 真的很奇妙
Yes. It's wonderful actually.
我能问你个问题么?
May I ask you something?
当然
Please do.
你愿意付出多大代价...
How far would you go...
去得到你一路过来所想要的那个答案?
to get what you came all this way for?
那个答案
Your answers.
你准备怎么做呢?
What are you willing to do?
我愿意付出一切的一切
Anything and everything.
那就为这喝一杯吧
That's worth drinking to, I'd imagine.
祝你好运 朋友
Here's mud in your eye, pal.
祝你身体健康
Good health.
是那些东西
It's those things.
这些东西是真的么?
Are they real?
他们当然是真的
Of course they're real.
老天 我是说...
Jesus Christ. I mean....
看看这一堆
Look at the pile.
看看它们堆的有多高
Look how high up they are.
看上去...
It looks like...
他们在逃避什么东西
they were running from something.
好 别碰他们 好吗?
Okay. Don't touch, okay?
伙计 看他们身体好像由里向外爆出
Man, this thing is opened up from the inside.
就像内爆炸一样
Almost like it exploded.
就像一幅大屠杀的场景一样 你懂吗?
Looks like a scene out some sort of holocaust painting, you know?
那些杀掉他们的东西应该早就不在了 是吧?
So, whatever killed them is long gone, right?
密尔本 费菲尔德
Millburn, Fifield.
我是普罗米修斯号
This is Prometheus.
你们在哪里?
What is your position?
普罗米修斯号 我是密尔本
Prometheus, this is Millburn.
我们在7401477 怎么了?
We are at 7-4-0-1-4-7-7. Why?
距你们西边1公里处有个脉冲
Just got a ping about one click west of you.
"脉冲"是什么意思?
What do you mean "a ping"?
不管怎样...
Well, whatever...
那个探测器探到什么...
that probe is picking up...
它不是死的
it's not dead.
是活着的东西
It's reading a life form.
- 什么?  - 好吧 什么是"活着的东西"?
- What? - Okay, what do you mean, "a life form"?
它...那东西在动么?
Is it... Is it moving?
没 我看不是
No, I don't think so.
舰长 你...
Captain, you're...
显然肯定没看到...
obviously not seeing...
我们现在看到的东西
what we're seeing here.
如果你看到 你就不会说什么脉冲了
If you were, you wouldn't be talking about a ping.
我懂 小子们
I know, boys.
自从风暴开始就零星地收到探测器读数
Your signal has been coming in sporadically since the storm hit.
这儿可是一团糟啊!
That's no good to us down here!
它...它在动吗?现在这些东西还在动吗?
Is it... Is it moving? Are these things moving?
没有 实际上它消失了
No. No, it just disappeared, actually.
肯定是个故障
Must be a glitch.
你说的什么意思 "故障"?
What do you mean, "a glitch"?
好了 伙计们
All right, boys.
睡好
Sleep tight.
我们就不用彼此打搅对方了
Try not to bugger each other.
舰长 你说的是什么意思 "故障"?
Captain, what do you mean, "a glitch"?
密尔本 他刚刚说什么来着?等等
Millburn, what does he mean? Wait.
他说...
Now, he said...
- 他说的是在我们西面 是吗? - 是啊
- He said one click west, yeah? - Yeah.
那我们...
Now, we....
我们不会去哪儿的吧?
We don't want to check that out, do we?
当然不了
Shit, no.
那我们去哪儿?
Where are we gonna go?
往东
East.
对 往东
Yeah, east.
该死的故障
A fucking glitch, man.
"脉冲 故障 活物" 什么鬼东西?
"Pings, glitch, life form." What the fuck?
基于这些全息影像记录中的行为...
Based on the behavior of the subject in these holographic recordings...
我仍旧困惑到底什么使得目标的头爆裂开
we're attempting to identify what caused the head to combust.
我忍不住想知道这儿到底发生了什么?
I can't help but wonder was there an outbreak here?
按铃了么 女士?
You rang, ma'am?
我有一些重要的事情要告诉你 那是什么?
I have something important to tell you. What is that?
这是...
This is...
我保存在冰冻香槟中的一朵玫瑰
a rose that I had frozen with the champagne.
当我们找到我们要找的东西时我将会给你
I was gonna give it to you when we found what we came for.
我们确实找到了我们要找的
We did find what we came for.
他们曾在这 这是...
They were here. This is...
历史上最重要的发现...
The most significant discovery in the history...
人类历史  我当然知道
of mankind. Oh, I know.
了不起 真的了不起
It's incredible, it really is.
但我想和他们谈谈
But I wanted to talk to them.
你难道不想知道他们来这干吗?
I mean, don't you want to know why they came?
他们为何抛弃我们?
Why they abandoned us?
我想要知道答案 宝贝
I just want answers, baby.
你是对的 查理
We were right, Charlie.
我有证据
I have proof.
看
Look.
他们的基因物质远比我们久远
Their genetic material predates ours.
我们源于他们
We come from them.
- 你在开玩笑  - 不
- You're kidding me. - No.
好
Okay.
好 你现在应该把你爸的十字架拿下来了
Okay. I guess you can take your father's cross off now.
我为什么要这么做?
Why would I want to do that?
因为他们创造了我们
Because they made us.
其实呢 我们从来不知道
Well, exactly. We'll never know.
这是我们知道的:
But here's what we do know:
那就是创造生命其实不算什么
That there is nothing special about the creation of life.
对吧?任何人都能创造生命
Right? Anybody can do it.
你只需少量的DNA即可 对不对?
All you need is a dash of DNA and half a brain, right?
我不能
I can't.
我不能创造生命（不能受孕）
I can't create life.
那我怎么说呢?
What does that say about me?
艾丽 我不是...这个意思...
Ellie, that's not... I didn't mean...
我没在谈论...
I wasn't talking about...
孩子么?
Children?
是我们
Us.
伊丽莎白·肖...
Elizabeth Shaw...
你是我这一生遇到的最特别的人...
you are the most special person I have ever met in my life...
我爱你
and I love you.
这到底要花多久?
How much longer will this take?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只是舰长
I'm just a captain.
你那玩意儿发出声响就像只垂死的猫
That thing sounds like a dying cat, by the way.
我以为你懂这玩意儿...
I'll have you know that this thing...
它曾经属于史蒂芬·斯蒂尔（水牛春田乐队成员）
once belonged to Stephen Stills.
我有必要知道这些么?
Am I supposed to know who that is?
你知道...
You know...
如果你想上床...
if you wanna get laid...
你大可不必假装着...
you really don't have to pretend...
对这扫描金字塔有兴趣
to be interested in the pyramid scan.
你只需说 "嘿 我们上床吧"
You could just say, "Hey, I'm trying to get laid."
我的确可以这么说 不是么?
I could. I could say that, right?
但这不会有意义的...
But it wouldn't make sense...
我为何让自己飞行5亿英里...
why I would fly myself half a billion miles...
远离地球上的每个男人...
from every man on Earth...
如果我想上床的话 是不是呢?
if I wanted to get laid, would it?
嘿 维克丝
Hey, Vickers.
我只想问...
I was wondering....
你是机器人么?
Are you a robot?
到我房间
My room.
10分钟
Ten minutes.
∮ 如果你不能和你爱的人在一起 ∮
∮ Well, if you can't be with the one you love ∮
∮ 爱一个人 ∮
∮ Love the one ∮
∮ 就在一起 ∮
∮ You're with ∮
∮ 爱一个人就在一起 ∮
∮ Love the one you're with ∮
密尔本
Millburn.
这里满都是些黑乎乎的东西?
What's all this black stuff?
西班牙凉菜汤
Gazpacho.
那是烟草么?
Is that tobacco?
你在你的呼吸器里吸烟么?
Is that tobacco in your respirator?
是的 当然
Yeah, sure.
我爱大烟
Tobacco.
作为科学家
On behalf of scientists everywhere,
我真是耻于和你同伍...
I am ashamed to count you amongst us...
费菲尔德
Fifield.
真的
Really.
- 嘿 密尔本  - 什么?
- Hey, Millburn. - Yeah?
你看到这个东西了?
You see this thing?
你认为这个是什么?某种神吗?
What do you think this thing was? Some kind of a god?
他们崇拜的?哪种?
Something they worshiped? What?
- 它有点像是...  - 那是啥?
- It kind of looks like... - What's that?
那究竟是什么东西?
What the hell is that?
天啊 好
Oh, my God. Okay.
没事冷静 保持安静
Just stay calm. Stay quiet.
没事的 我能处理
This is okay, I can handle this.
嘿 小东西
Hey, baby.
收到 普罗米修斯号
Come in, Prometheus.
我们这里碰到一种爬虫类生物
We have an elongate reptile-type creature.
可能30到40英寸长 透明皮肤
Maybe 30, 40 inches, with transparent skin.
真是漂亮
And it's beautiful.
好!
Okay!
普罗米修斯号
Prometheus...
我们找到两个
we have two.
看看它 看看它 宝贝
Look at you. Look at you, baby.
天啊 看看它的尺寸 怎么样?
Jesus, look at the size of that. What is it?
- 你需要冷静下来  - 谁说我要冷静?
- You need to stay calm. - What's there to be calm about?
你应该冷静 因为她真是美丽
You need to stay calm because she is beautiful.
你怎么知道那个是女的?
What makes you think that's female?
是一位女士 看!
She's a lady. Look!
她被催眠了
She's mesmerized.
过来啊 过来啊
Come here. Come here.
没事的
It's okay.
没事的 没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
宝贝
Hey, baby.
你真有力气!
You're strong!
现在你可以来帮我了
You should help me now.
拿掉它
Get it off.
从这儿割 伙计!
Cut it here, man!
我可不碰这玩意儿!
I ain't touching that!
天啊 天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- 越来越紧了  - 我不碰这玩意儿!
- It's getting tighter. - I ain't touching it!
割掉它啊 伙计 看在上帝份上!
Cut the thing, man, for God's sake!
天啊 这下更糟了!
God, you're making it worse!
缠得越来越紧了!缠得...
It's tightening! It's tight...
它快弄断我的手臂了!
It's breaking my arm!
糟了!
Shit!
割掉它!
Cut it off!
糟了!
Shit!
我的天啊!
Oh, my God!
天啊!天啊!
Oh, my God! Oh, Jesus!
它进到我的衣服里了!
It's in my suit.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
肖 你在吗?
Shaw, you up?
在 怎么了?
Yeah, what's up?
风暴过去了 但我联系不到密尔本或是费菲尔德
The storm passed, but I can't reach Millburn or Fifield.
放一些人下去 看看能否发现他们
Taking a few men down, see if I can rustle them up.
好
Okay.
你知道他们大致在哪儿么?
Any idea where they are?
上次和他们通话的时候他们就在你们发现头的地方
Last time they radioed in was where you found your head.
好 我来了
Okay, we're coming.
好的
All right.
钱斯 你跟我来 快点
Chance, you're coming with me. Come on.
知道了 头儿
All right, boss.
- 拉威尔 你认为那是故障么? - 不是 舰长
- Ravel, did you fix that glitch? - No, captain.
- 可能是硬件的问题  - 什么故障 舰长?
- It's gotta be in the hardware. - What glitch, captain?
其中一个探测器检测到有活着的生物
One of them probes picked up a life form.
但是不到一会讯号就消失了
Pops up every hour for a couple of seconds and then it's gone.
我能找到那些探测器并修好它
I can find the probe and fix it.
随你便
Knock yourself out.
小心点 博士
Be careful, doctors.
费菲尔德!
Fifield!
密尔本!
Millburn?
好吧 继续前进
All right, come on down.
大卫 你一个人么?
David, are you alone?
是的 维克丝小姐
Yes, Miss Vickers.
给我房间视频信号
Uplink your feed to my room.
收到
Copy.
你这狗娘养的
You son of a bitch.
竟敢掐了我的讯号
You cut me off.
这是什么?
What is this?
- 查理?  - 我滑了下
- Charlie? - I just tripped.
天啊 你病了!
Oh, my God, you're sick!
我没事 继续
I'm okay, baby. Come on.
费菲尔德!
Fifield?
密尔本!
Millburn?
钱斯 我是你可不会碰
Hey, Chance. I wouldn't touch that if I were you.
肖博士?
Dr. Shaw?
怎么?
Yeah?
你知道这里漏出瓮的液体是什么吗?
Do we have any idea what is oozing out of these vases?
不 上次我们来的时候它们可不是这样的
No. They weren't like this last time we were here.
舰长?
Captain?
怎么?
What?
哪一位?
Who is it? Which one?
- 那个是谁? - 是密尔本
- Who is it? - It's Millburn.
- 艾丽  - 别碰他 停下
- Ellie. - Don't touch him. Hold on.
艾丽 亲爱的
Ellie, honey.
查理 怎么了?
Charlie, what's wrong?
我要你看着我 好吗?
I need you to look at me, okay?
可能是感染...
You know infections...
那你看到了什么?
so, what do you see?
不太妙 宝贝
This is not good, baby.
看着我 告诉我你看到了什么
You look at me, you tell me what you see.
天啊
Oh, my God.
福特 快过来
Ford, get over here.
没关系 杰尼克?
It's okay. Janek?
- 什么? - 我们还是快离开!
- What? - We have to go now!
你到底看到了什么?
What do you see?
亲爱的 你看到什么?
Honey, what do you see?
霍罗威病了 他不太好
Holloway's sick. He's not good.
食道里像是什么东西
I see movement in his esophagus.
- 快点 宝贝  - 不 我没事
- Come on, baby. - No. I'm okay.
杰尼克!
Janek!
舰长过来帮我!
Come over and help me!
- 我没事  - 福特 过来看看 这是怎么回事?
- I'm okay. - Ford, get over there. What's happening?
- 我没事  - 走吧!
- I'm okay. - Let's go!
帮我看着他
Help me with him.
抓紧 我们快点离开
I got you. We're gonna get you out of here.
普罗米修斯号...
Prometheus...
收到
come in.
- 注意头顶  - 好的 我没事
- Watch your head. - Okay. I'm okay.
- 霍罗威  - 抬起他
- Holloway. - Get him up.
- 快点  - 普罗米修斯号 收到
- Come on. - Prometheus, come in.
有人么?
Is anyone there?
我是维克丝
This is Vickers.
我需要医疗队在气舱处等候
I need a medical team standing by the airlock.
全面隔离检疫处理
Full quarantine fail-safe.
霍罗威病了
Holloway's sick.
什么病?
Sick with what?
- 照做就是了  - 我们把他送回船上
- Just do it. - Let's get him back to the ship.
- 那下边不安全  - 查理?
- It's not safe down here. - Charlie?
我去换衣
I'm suiting up.
- 查理 跟我说  - 走!
- Charlie, talk to me. - Move!
- 什么东西在后面?  - 走吧!
- What was that back there? - Let's go, people!
我们得走!我们得走!
We've gotta move! We've gotta move!
他看上去不太妙
He don't look too good.
他抓着什么东西么?我们的头盔丢了
Did he catch something down there? We had our helmets off.
不清楚
I don't know.
普罗米修斯号 我是杰尼克
Prometheus, this is Janek.
确保后门是开着的
Make sure that back door is open.
遵命 长官
Aye, captain.
天啊!我很抱歉!
Oh, God. I'm so sorry.
用力!
Come on!
求你了!
Please!
普罗米修斯号!为什么不开门?
Prometheus! Why is that door not open?
维克丝 这是命令!
Vickers, that is an order!
打开那见鬼的门!
Get that goddamn door open!
- 看着我 太迟了 我病了  - 不 还没有
- Look at me. It's too late, I'm sick. - No, it's not.
继续!
Come on!
福特 帮我!
Ford, help me!
气闸员 如果你听到了 我是杰尼克
Airlock crew, if you can hear me, it's Janek.
马上打开后门!
Open that back door right now!
开门!
Hold that door!
普罗米修斯号...
Prometheus...
你收到没?
do you copy?
见鬼 快开门!这是命令!
Goddamn it, open that door! That is an order!
开门!
Open it.
这怎么回事?
What the hell is this?
维克丝 他是位病人
Vickers, this is a sick man.
我知道 这正是不能让他上船的原因!
I see that. That's why he's not coming on!
查理!
Charlie!
钱斯 过来!
Chance, get over here!
求你了!
Please!
我们得救救他!
We can still help him!
除霍罗威外 全体人员马上回到船上!
Help yourself. Everybody but Holloway back on this ship!
我不能丢下他!
I won't leave him!
等等!我们可以把他放进医疗舱!
Wait! We could put him on the Med-Pod!
求你别这么做!
Please don't do this.
没事的 艾丽
It's okay, Ellie.
维克丝!
Vickers!
你想怎么样?
What are you doing?
我爱你 宝贝
I love you, baby.
- 我爱你 - 不要
- I love you. - No.
我警告你 别过来!
I'm telling you, stay back!
动手吧
Do it.
退回去!
Stay back!
不 不 查理!
No! No, Charlie!
- 来吧 - 不!
- Do it. - No!
不!
No!
查理!
Charlie!
不!
No!
致以我最深切的慰问
My deepest condolences.
我得拿走它
I'm going to have to take this.
它可能被感染了
It may be contaminated.
如果它会传染 我们都有危险
If there's a contagion, we were all exposed.
你要... 我们必须对接触金字塔的人进行验血
You need... We need to run blood work on everyone who set foot in the pyramid.
是 当然
Yes, of course.
好?
Yes?
我知道这不太妥当...
I understand how inappropriate this is...
鉴于这种情况下
given the circumstances.
但是当你被下令隔离...
But as you ordered quarantine fail-safes...
我有责任要这样问
it's my responsibility to ask.
你最近和霍罗威博士有过亲密接触吗?
Have you and Dr. Holloway had any intimate contact recently?
自从你和他走得很近后...
Since you and he were so close...
我只是想尽可能搞清楚...
I want to be as thorough as poss...
哎呀
My, my.
你怀孕了
You're pregnant.
什么?
What?
看上去 有三个月大了
From the look of it, three months so.
不 那不可能
No, that's impossible.
我不可能怀孕
I can't be pregnant.
你有和霍罗威博士发生性关系吗?
Did you have intercourse with Dr. Holloway?
是的...
Yes...
只是10小时以前
but 10 hours ago.
根本不可能我会怀孕
There's no bloody way I'm three months pregnant.
博士...
Well, doctor...
看上去胎儿也挺不正常的
it's not exactly a traditional fetus.
我想看看
I want to see it.
我不认为这是个好主意
Don't think that's a good idea.
大卫 我想看看
David, I want to see it.
现在 博士...
Now, doctor...
我要看看它
I want to see it.
我要把它取出来
I want it out of me.
我们这里没有适合的人...
We don't have the personnel...
能够做这种处理
to perform a procedure like that.
- 最好的选择是... - 我要拿掉这个东西
- Our best option... - I want it out.
把你放入冷冻休眠舱 直到我们返回地球
Put you back into cryostasis until we return to Earth.
求你了 把它取出来
Please, get it out of me.
把它取出来!
Get it out of me!
求你了
Please.
我给你一样东西
Here, let me give you something.
这就对了 那里 那里
That's it. There, there.
马上就会有人来...
Someone will be along shortly...
把你送去冷冻舱
to bring you back to Cryo Deck.
你肯定觉得你的神抛弃了你
It must feel like your God abandoned you.
什么?
What?
死了...
To lose...
霍罗威博士跟你爸爸死于一样的状况之下
Dr. Holloway after your father died under such similar circumstances.
是什么杀死他的?
What was it that killed him?
伊波拉?
Ebola?
你怎么... 你是怎么知道的?
How do you... How do you know that?
我看了你的梦境
I watched your dreams.
肖博士?
Dr. Shaw?
我们在这儿把你放入抗感染外套里面
We're here to put you in an anti-contamination suit,
然后送你去冷冻舱里休眠
take you back to Cryo Deck go to beddy-byes.
肖博士?
Dr. Shaw?
她被麻醉了 做好准备
She's doped. Prepare her.
紧急救治手术启动
Emergency procedures initiated.
请口头描述你的病情
Please verbally state the nature of your injury.
我需要剖腹产手术
I need a Caesarean.
错误 医疗舱为男性病人标准制定使用...
Error. This Med-Pod is calibrated for male patients...
不能进行你所要求的手术
and does not offer the procedure you have requested.
请查看其它的医疗帮助
Seek medical assistance elsewhere.
手术（人工自定义手术）
Surgery.
腹部
Abdominal.
穿透...
Penetrating...
深部损伤
injuries.
异物
Foreign body.
启动
Initiate.
外科手术程序开始
Surgical procedure to begin.
运行诊断程序
Running diagnostics.
快点
Oh, come on.
快出去!快啊!
Get it out! Come on!
求你了!
Please!
天啊!
Oh, God!
- 快点!  - 开始麻醉
- Come on! - Initiating anesthetics.
求你了!
Please!
开始外科手术
Commence surgical procedure.
天啊
Oh, God.
天啊!
Oh, God!
我的天!
天啊!天啊!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
哦 天啊!
Oh, my God!
快点!
Come on!
舰桥呼叫机库 我是舰长
Bridge to hangar. This is the captain.
- 收到 舰长  - 你能看到我所看到的么?
- Yes, captain. - Can you see what I see?
费菲尔德的监视镜头突然出现了
Fifield's monitor just popped up.
什么?在哪儿?
What? Where?
依据我所看到的
According to what I'm looking at,
他就在该死的船外面
it's outside the goddamn ship.
巴恩斯 打开门!
Barnes, open the door!
费菲尔德 你收到没?说话
Fifield, do you copy me? Come on in.
费菲尔德?
Fifield?
等一下
Wait a second.
华莱士
Hey, Wallace.
看下这个什么情况
Take a look at this.
费菲尔德?
Fifield?
下面到底出了什么事?
What the hell is going on down there?
我下去看看
I'm coming down there.
钱斯 你把衣服换上
Chance, you're suiting up.
- 快点  - 别把它留在船上!
- Come on. - Don't let it on the ship!
杀了他!
Take him out!
Got him!
杀啊!
Do it!
- 准备好了 钱斯? -好了
- You ready, Chance? - Yes.
快点!
Come on!
到车里面来!
Get in the rover!
我们得离开这里!
We gotta get out of here!
快!
Go!
那是什么?
What is that?
你一直在深眠中
You've been asleep.
你一直就在船上 为什么?
You were on the ship all this time. Why?
我...
Well, I....
我已经时日无多了
I have a few days of life left in me.
我不想浪费时间...
I didn't wanna waste them...
直到你能实现你的承诺
until you could deliver what you promised.
见我的造物主
To meet my maker.
好了 先生
There we are, sir.
- 干干净净  - 你怎么不告诉他造物主们都死了呢?
- Nice and clean. - Haven't you told him they're all gone?
但他们没全死 肖博士
But they're not all gone, Dr. Shaw.
其中一个还活着
One of them is still alive.
我们现在就准备去见他
We're on our way to see him now.
什么?
What?
让我转过去
Turn me around.
是你让我相信...
You convinced me that...
如果这些造物主创造了我们...
if these things made us...
同样他们也可以挽救我们
then surely they could save us.
我的拐杖 帮下
My stick, please.
总之他们会救我
Well, save me, anyway.
救你什么啊?
Save you from what?
当然是我的命啊
Death, of course.
帮我起来
Stand me up.
我没事了
I'm all right.
是
Yes, sir.
你根本就不了解
But you don't understand.
你不了解
You don't know.
这地方根本就不是我们想象的地方 他们也不是...
This place isn't what we thought it was. They aren't...
我们想象的样子
what we thought they were.
我错了
I was wrong.
我们真是大错特错
We were so wrong.
查理...
Charlie....
霍罗威博士死了
Dr. Holloway's dead.
我们必须离开!
We must leave!
你觉得现在查理会做什么...
And what would Charlie do...
现在我们如此之接近...
now that we're so close...
可以解答人类历史上最有意义的问题吗?
to answering the most meaningful questions ever asked by mankind?
你怎能就此一走了之而什么都不过问呢?
How can you leave without knowing what they are?
或是你丧失信仰了么 肖?
Or have you lost your faith, Shaw?
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
进来
Come in.
你到底要去哪里 博士?
Where the hell are you going, doc?
你知道这是什么地方吗?
You know what this place is?
那些工程师?这里可不是他们的家
Those Engineers? This ain't their home.
这是个基地 更像是军事基地
It's an installation. Maybe even military.
他们在这个地方建造基地是因为他们可不会蠢到...
They put it out here because they're not stupid enough...
在自己家门口实验这种大规模杀伤性武器
to make weapons of mass destruction on their own doorstep.
就是那些在瓮里的狗屁东西
That's what all that shit is in those vases.
他们在这里制造了它们
They made it here.
它们逃了出来 它们进行反扑 结束了
It got out, it turned on them. The end.
是时候回家了
It's time for us to go home.
他们中的一个还活着
One of them is still alive.
你不想知道他会说些什么吗?
Don't you want to know what they have to say?
我不在乎
I don't care.
对
Right.
你的职责只是驾驶飞船而已
All you do is fly the ship.
很对
That's right.
但是你肯定在意些东西 舰长
But you must care about something, captain.
不然你怎么会来这里?
If you didn't, why are you here?
要不这样吧?
How about this?
不管发生什么事情
No matter what happens down there...
我可不会允许带着这些东西跟我们回家
I can't bring none of that shit back home with us.
绝不能让此事发生
Can't let it happen.
所以我要竭尽全力确保此事不会发生
I'll do whatever I have to to see that it doesn't.
你要说到做到 舰长
Make sure you do, captain.
你终于来了
So you came after all.
我知道你想去见他
I thought you wanted me to.
虽然你极力阻止我来到这里...
After all your attempts to stop me from coming here...
我也吓了你一跳吧
I'm surprised to see you.
行了 你下去吧
It's all right. Leave us.
是
Yes, sir.
如果你前去的话 你会死的
If you're going down there, you will die.
你总是往不好的那面看
Very negative way of looking at things.
你早就应该呆在家里
That's exactly why you should have stayed at home.
你真的以为我能安心的坐在董事会会议室几年...
Did you really think I was gonna sit in a boardroom for years...
去和人争论谁来当家管事...
arguing over who was in charge...
而你去寻找什么奇迹...
while you go look for some miracle on some...
或是太空深处的倒霉石头吗?
godforsaken rock in the middle of space?
国王是有统治权 但他也会死
A king has his reign, and then he dies.
这是不可避免的
It's inevitable.
这是自然法则决定的事情
That is the natural order of things.
说完了?
Anything else?
说完了...
No...
父亲
Father.
就这么多
That's it.
我没料到你骨子里这么有能耐
I didn't think you had it in you.
抱歉
Sorry.
你做得好
Poor choice of words.
你真是有非凡的求生本能 伊丽莎白
Extraordinary survival instincts, Elizabeth.
要是维兰德死了没人帮你编制程序了会怎样?
What happens when Weyland is not around to program you?
我想我就自由了
I suppose I'll be free.
那就是你想要的?
You want that?
"想"?
"Want"?
我可不熟悉这个概念
Not a concept I'm familiar with.
话虽如此...
That being said...
不是每个人都想自己的父母死啊?
doesn't everyone want their parents dead?
我也不想
I didn't.
肖博士
Dr. Shaw.
很高兴你能加入我们
So pleased you could join us.
你要是愿意就摘下头盔好了 先生
You can take your helmet off if you like, sir.
什么?
What?
空气是可以呼吸的
The air is perfectly breathable.
你确定?
Are you sure?
是的
Positive.
等下 我们仍然不知道霍罗威是如何感染的
Wait. We still don't know how Holloway got infected.
假如是空气传染的
If it's in the air.
不是空气传染
It's not.
你怎么会知道?
How do you know that?
看来我没事
Smells fine to me.
- 我们继续? - 请吧
- Shall we?   - Please.
桥头就在前面
The bridge is just up ahead.
这是哪里?
What is this?
这里是货物舱
It's a cargo hold.
杰尼克?你看到了么?
Janek? Are you seeing this?
那儿有多少 肖?
How many is there, Shaw?
数千
Thousands.
这算什么?
What the hell?
拉威尔 给我那些探测器读数
Ravel, give me those schematics.
在桌面上显示
Putting it on the table now.
除掉那个圆顶
Strip away the dome.
分离那个区域 来了
Isolate that area, bring it up.
来了 舰长
Bringing it up, captain.
放大
Enlarge that.
旋转
Rotate it.
那是艘飞船
That is a ship.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
是艘该死的飞船
It's a goddamn ship.
高等物种 毫无疑问
A superior species, no doubt.
他们的深眠舱出人意料 我相信
Their hypersleep chambers will impress, I trust.
那么他们是准备前往某个地方
So they were traveling somewhere.
我已经弄清了大概的情况
I've managed to work out the broad strokes.
很显然他们正准备离开...
It's fairly evident they were in the process of leaving...
在大难临头之前
before things went to pot.
前往哪里?
Leaving to go where?
地球
Earth.
为何?
Why?
有时候创造前必先毁灭
Sometimes to create one must first destroy.
他在哪里 大卫?
Where is he, David?
这边 长官
This way, sir.
你确定他还活着?
Are you sure he's alive?
当然
Absolutely.
你能和他对话?
And you can speak to him?
我想可以
I believe I can.
我没事 我没事
I'm all right, I'm all right.
跟他说吧 大卫
Speak to him, David.
跟他说我们来过 就像他问的一样
Tell him we came, just like he asked.
问他们从何而来
Ask where they're from.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
问他在货物舱里是什么东西
Ask him what's in his cargo.
那些东西杀人了
It killed his people.
肖 够了
Shaw, enough.
- 大卫 - 你在这里制造这东西...
- David. - You made it here...
是用来对付我们的 为什么?
and it was meant for us. Why?
够了 看在上帝的份上 让她闭嘴
Enough. For God's sake, shut her up.
你要知道这是为什么!
I need to know why!
我们做错了什么?你为什么恨我们?
What did we do wrong? Why do you hate us?
她要是再再张嘴 就毙了她
She opens her mouth again, shoot her.
大卫 继续 告诉他我此行目的
David, continue. Tell him why I came.
不!
No!
福特!跑!
Ford! Move!
算是白费功夫
There's nothing.
我知道
I know.
你一路走好 维兰德先生
Have a good journey, Mr. Weyland.
是时候回家了
Time to go home.
钱斯先生 带我们回家
Mr. Chance, take us home.
哦不!
Oh, no!
舰长
Hey, cap.
那到底是什么?
What the hell was that?
普罗米修斯号!
Prometheus!
收到没?
Come in!
肖 是你吗?
Shaw, is that you?
收到
Copy.
杰尼克...
Janek...
听我说
listen to me.
那艘船启动出发了!
This ship is taking off!
- 什么?  - 她到底再说些什么?
- What? - What is she talking about?
你不能丢下它!
You can't let it leave!
你必须阻止它!
You have to stop it!
我们可不会管 肖 我们回家了
We're not stopping anything, Shaw. We're going home.
杰尼克 如果我们不阻止这艘船...
Janek, if you don't stop it...
那我们就没得家可回了
there won't be any home to go back to.
那艘船装载着死亡 它向着地球去了
It's carrying death, and it's headed for Earth.
- 肖 那可不是什么战舰  - 我知道
- Shaw, this is not a warship. - I know.
走吧
Let's go.
我知道
I know that.
但你必须这么做
But you must do it.
舰长 我们走吧!
Captain, let's go!
杰尼克 求求你相信我!求你了!
Janek, please believe me! Please!
我告诉你快让这飞船飞起来
I told you to get this ship going.
拉威尔先生
Mr. Ravel.
加热离子推进器
Warm up the ion propulsion.
- 你胡说些什么?  - 长官
- What are you talking about? - Sir.
在这种大气下加热离子...
Burning ion in the atmosphere...
- 把我们变成子弹 就是这个意思  - 你到底想干什么?
- Turns us into a bullet. That's the point. - What are you doing?
这船是我的 我要你带我们回家!
This is my ship. I'm telling you to take us home!
维克丝 我要弹射掉你的救生独立舱 可维持两年生命
Vickers, I'll eject your module onto that surface. Two years of life.
你是想要它 还是想留在这里和我在一起?
You want it, or you want to stay with me?
你有40秒去逃生舱
You got 40 seconds to get to the escape pod.
你疯了
You're crazy.
先生们我能自己驾驶
Gentlemen I can handle this myself.
你们和维克丝小姐一起走吧
Feel free to join Miss Vickers.
我尊敬你 舰长
All due respect, captain.
你可不是驾驶员 你需要我们所有的帮助
You're a shit pilot and you're gonna need all the help you can get.
∮ 如果你不能和你爱的人在一起 ∮
∮ Well, if you can't be with the one you love ∮
如果你觉得赌注取消了...
If you think this means the bet's off...
那你可就错了
you're wrong.
为何你不去另一个世界付给我呢?
Why don't you pay me on the other side?
好吧 我们尽量靠近点
All right, get us as close as we can.
只有一次机会
Only got one shot at this.
丢掉负重!
Lifeboats away!
还剩20秒撤离
Twenty seconds to evacuate.
- 添加混合燃料  - 离子推力启动
- Countdown initiated. - Ion propulsion is online.
十
Ten.
九
Nine.
来吧!
Come on!
八
Eight.
- 三  - 先生们 动手吧
- Three. - Gentleman, let's do this.
二
Two.
警告即将撞击
Impact imminent.
离手!
Hands off!
天啊
Oh, God.
不 不
No. No.
不!不!不!
No! No! No!
老天
Oh, God.
警告: 还剩下2分钟的氧气量
Warning: You have two minutes of oxygen remaining.
警告: 还剩下30秒的氧气量
Warning: You have 30 seconds of oxygen remaining.
气舱关闭
Airlock sealed.
氧气含量现在稳定
Oxygen levels now stabilizing.
伊丽莎白 听得到我么?
Elizabeth, are you there?
我是大卫
This is David.
是的 是的 我听到了
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I'm here.
你应该马上离开
You need to get out immediately.
他找你来了
He's coming for you.
谁来了?
Who's coming?
气舱被打开
Airlock breach.
去死吧!
Die!
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
天啊
Oh, God.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我对不起你 查理 我做不到
I'm sorry, Charlie, I can't do it.
我就是做不到
I can't do it anymore.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
你在吗?
Are you there?
肖博士...
Dr. Shaw...
你听得到我么?
can you hear me?
是的
Yes.
是的 我听得到
Yes, I can hear you.
我真怕你死了
I was afraid you were dead.
你根本不知道什么叫怕
You have no idea what afraid is.
我知道我们有所分歧...
I know we've had our differences...
但是...
but, please...
我需要你的帮助
I need to ask you for your help.
我为什么要帮你?
Why the hell would I help you?
因为没有我 你将不能离开这个地方
Because, without me, you'll never leave this place.
反正我们哪个都不可能离开
Neither one of us is leaving this place.
这不是唯一的飞船
It's not the only ship.
有很多这样的船
There are many others.
我能驾驶他们
I can operate them.
肖博士?
Dr. Shaw?
肖博士!
Dr. Shaw!
在这里
Over here.
我的十字架呢?
Where is my cross?
在我的工具腰带里
The pouch in my utility belt.
经历了这一切...
Even after all this...
你还存有信仰 是吗?
you still believe, don't you?
你说你懂得他们的导航...
You said you could understand their navigation...
用他们的星图
use their maps.
当然
Yes, of course.
只要我们去到另一艘飞船里...
Once we get to one of their other ships...
就可以直接找到一条回地球的路径
finding a path to Earth should be relatively straightforward.
我不想回到我们来的那个地方
I don't want to go back to where we came from.
我想去到他们的所在之处
I want to go where they came from.
你认为你做的到么 大卫?
Do you think you can do that, David?
是的
Yes.
我相信我做的到
I believe I can.
我能问下你去哪儿想达成什么目的么?
May I ask what you hope to achieve by going there?
他们创造了我们
They created us.
然后他们想要杀死我们
Then they tried to kill us.
他们改变了主意
They changed their minds.
我有权知道这是为什么
I deserve to know why.
这个答案可能无关紧要
The answer is irrelevant.
他们为什么改变主意真的没关系吗?
Does it matter why they changed their minds?
是的
Yes.
这当然要紧
Yes, it does.
我不明白
I don't understand.
这么说...
Well...
我猜那是因为我是人类...
I guess that's because I'm a human being...
而你是个机器人
and you're a robot.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
没事
It's quite all right.
普罗米修斯号最后汇报
Final report of the vessel Prometheus.
船和所有船员都已损失
The ship and her entire crew are gone.
如果你们收到此信号...
If you're receiving this transmission...
不要企图追溯它的源头
make no attempt to come to its point of origin.
这里只有死亡 我已弃之离去
There is only death here now, and I'm leaving it behind.
今天公元2094年的新年第一天
It is New Year's Day the year of our Lord, 2094.
我的名字叫伊丽莎白·肖...
My name is Elizabeth Shaw...
普罗米修斯号最后的幸存者
the last survivor of the Prometheus.
我仍在探索
And I am still searching.